Finding aid to the Smith College Club of Palm Beaches records CA.MS.00318
Smith College Archives
Smith College Club of Palm Beaches records
1960-2005
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Palm Beaches
CA.MS.00318
1.25 linear feet (3 containers)
The Smith College Club of Palm Beaches began in 1959 as an informal sect of the nearby Smith Club of Fort Lauderdale. This collection contains minutes, membership directories, event programs, financial records, photographs, newspaper clippings, correspondence, and a scrapbook documenting the Smith Club of Palm Beaches's activities.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Club of Palm Beaches began in 1959 as an informal sect of the nearby Smith Club of Fort Lauderdale. This new group consisted of Mrs. David Chandler Prince (1911), Mrs. Lee Porter (1912), and Mrs. John Eldredge Smith (1931). These three women resided in the Palm Beaches, Florida, area and met informally with Mrs. Ralph Smith (1931) at local hotels and restaurants. It was not until the Smith College Club of Palm Beaches was officially recognized by the Alumnae Association in 1965 that they gathered at regular monthly luncheon meetings at Testa's Restaurant in Palm Beaches. The Club's by-laws were amended in 1973 and 1981. Members include Smith alumnae residing from Boca Raton to Vero Beaches, Florida.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of several decades' worth of minutes and meeting agendas, as well as extensive newspaper clippings documenting the club's activities. Official records of Alumnae Councils and donations to the Alumnae Fund for scholarships are also in the files. Additional material ranges from photographs of club events to fundraising efforts, events announcements and invitations, and membership directories from 1966 to 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith College Club of Palm Beaches records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- Alumnae Council, Smith College, 1963-1989 (Box 1)
- Announcements, 1962-2000 (Box 1)
- Annual Reports, 1966-1989 (Box 1)
- By-laws, 1973-1981 (Box 1)
- Club History, 1960-1991 (Box 1)
- Community Calling Program/Capital Campaign for Smith, 1966-1989 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Alumnae Association of Smith College, 1965-1988 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Career Development Office, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Miscellaneous, 1961-2001 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: Other Smith Clubs, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
- Directories, 1966-2005 (Box 2)
- Finances: Tax Exempt Status, 1974 (Box 2)
- Fundraising/Pecan Sales, 1969-1999 (Box 2)
- Guests: Conway, Jill Ker, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Guests: Hindmarsh, Ronald, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
- Minutes and Agendas, 1965-1982 (Box 2)
- Minutes and Agendas, 1983-2003 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1968-1988 (Box 3)
- Networking Questionnaire, 1993 (Box 3)
- Newsletters, 1966-2000 (Box 3)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1960-1998 (Box 3)
- Photographs, 1986-1992 (Box 3)
- President's Letters, 1966-2002 (Box 3)
- Presidents: Smith, Ethel, 1966-1968 (Box 3)
- Program Arrangements, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
- Scholarship Candidates/Alumnae Admissions Committee, 1963-1990 (Box 3)
- Scrapbook Contents, 1961-1966 (Box 3)